**Kevin Snijders** 

Date of birth: 6 april 1993 Birthplace: Purmerend Nationality: Dutch



A Web Developer with more than 2 years of Front-end experience and a passion for developing beautiful applications. As a graduate Software engineer also capable of working on the Back-end. Good communication skills and not afraid to share my opinion. Like learning new things and are open to working with any language.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Internship Full Stack Developer | Sofa Superstars | Amsterdam | 2017 — 2018

#### **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

- Wrote a thesis about "a cross-site messaging system with near-real-time delivery".
- Gathered and documented requirements with Use-Cases.
- Implemented an application from concept through deployment.
- Implemented a React component library with Rollup.is.
- Developed various RESTful APIs.
- Setup integration for using the WebSocket API.
- Gave a product demonstration every two weeks.

- Collaborated with team members to implement new features.
- Participated in Scrum meetings.
- Point of contact for the Front-end intern.

Internship Multimedia | youngbits | Purmerend |

2013 — 2014

#### **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

- Implemented WordPress websites from concept through deployment.
- Prototypes created with Photoshop.
- Assessed client ideas and wishes for technical feasibility.

**Front-end Developer** | Sofa Superstars | Amsterdam | 2015 — 2017

#### **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

- Implemented websites, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Code compatible with older browsers (Internet Explorer, Safari 5.x, etc.)
- Refactoring pieces of VanillaJS code to React components.
- Responsible for fixing hotfix issues as pixel perfect, responsiveness, and bugs.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.

#### PROJECTS

#### Web Developer | Portfolio | 2019 — 2019

- Implemented a Progressive Single-page
  Application from concept through deployment.
- Implemented Redux for state management.
- Configured webpack from scratch instead of using tools as create-react-app.
- Implemented a light and dark mode.
- LocalStorage is used whenever a user is in offline mode.
- Implemented Unit tests with Jest, Enzyme and react-test-renderer.
- Developed and implemented a Node Express server with a Postgres database and a RESTful API.

## EDUCATION

**Software Engineering |** Hogeschool van Amsterdam | Amsterdam | 2014 — 2018

**Relevant coursework:** Startup Analytics, Strategic Management, Prototyping, Automated Software validation, Parallel Computing, Research Design, Architecture & Design, Information Visualization, Object-Oriented Programming en Data Structures.

Applicatieontwikkelaar | Horizon college |

Purmerend | 2010 — 2014

## SKILLS & KNOWLEDGE

- Implementatie van features, websites en landing pages van concept tot deployment.
- Onderhouden, optimaliseren, problemen oplossen en verbeteren van websites.
- Code testen door middel van Unit tests.
- Experimenteren met nieuwe technieken.

*Front-end:* JavaScript, React, Redux, Sass, CSS-in-JS, TypeScript, Node.js, Bootstrap jQuery, and WordPress.

Back-end: Java, Python, Django, and Node.js.

Data: RESTful API, Firebase, PostgreSQL, and MySQL.

**Tools:** Git, npm, ESLint, Prettier, Gulp, Babel, and Webpack.

**Testing:** Jest, Enzyme, and CircleCI.

**Deployment:** Heroku, and Github pages.

Design tools: Zeplin.io, and InVisionApp Figma.

Project management: JIRA, Trello, and Agile (Scrum)

### SOFT SKILLS

Communication, Flexibility, Patience, Perseverance, Teamwork, Solution-oriented, Stress resistant, and Willingness to learn.

#### LANGUAGES

Dutch and English.

## REFERENCE

Upon request.